敵人攻擊，你跑了  那就是叛國
When the enemy attacked, you ran away.  That's treason.
現在要你腦漿迸裂
Now it's time  to splatter your brains everywhere.
拜託你！不要殺我！
Please! Please, don't kill me!
閉嘴！勇敢地去死吧！
Shut up! Die like a man!
可是我還有妻小
But I have a wife and family.
膽小鬼的下場就是這樣
That's what happens to cowards.
小聲點
Hey. You have to keep it down.
這裏在開重要會議
There's an important meeting going on.
對不起
Sorry.
我帶你去拷貝室  才不會干擾到別人
I'll set you up in the copy room.  You won't be in the way there.
這次票數會很接近
This is gonna be a close vote.
大部分同事…
Most of your colleagues
都不會想把這一大筆錢  只花在25選區內
are not gonna want to spend  this amount of money in just 25 districts.
先試著用勸說
Try persuasion first.
勸說重點在資料裏
Talking points are in your packets.
如果還需要更多詳細資訊  研究報告或統計資料
And ifyou want more detailed information,  research, statistics,
可以和我或吉莉安連絡
you can contact Gillian or myself.
如果需要給甜頭，去找道格
And when it comes to doling out favors,  talk to Doug.
如果給甜頭沒用  就直接來找我，彼得
If favors don't work,  come to me directly. Peter.
我會在賓州競選
I'll be campaigning in Pennsylvania.
本周我所有的活動  會在分水嶺內的各郡
All my events this week will be in counties  within the watershed,
所以我會專攻媒體
so I'll be working the media angle.
不過如果你們需要我  和任何人電話溝通
But ifyou need me  to get on the phone with anybody,
去找克裏絲汀娜  她會安排時間表
reach out to Christina.  She'll work it into my schedule.
我得直說，法蘭  二億元會很難讓人接受
I have to say, Frank,  $200 million is going to be a hard sell.
天然氣的遊說團體  已經全力反抗
The natural gas lobby's  already putting up a big fight.
我們需要針對就業
We need to make this about jobs.
可是鑽井業能提供的就業機會  比這個提案多得多
But the drilling industry  can offer far more jobs than this bill can.
提案沒威脅到那些工作
This bill doesn't threaten those jobs,
只是要讓鑽井業  負起更多責任
it just makes sure the drilling  is done responsibly.
此外還能提供更多就業
It adds more jobs on top of that.
善可工業已經來找過我  提供競選連任資金
I've already been approached  by SanCorp with re-election funds.
我也是
I have too.
有八個不同的鑽井公司  要透過他們捐獻金
They offered me a donation package  from eight different drilling companies.
- 瑞米丹頓嗎？  - 對
-Remy Danton?  -Yep.
瑞米找過你們哪些人？
How many of you been approached by Remy?
我知道，拒絕金錢不容易
Look, I know it's not easy  to turn down money.
可是如果共和黨  控制賓州的重劃選區
But if the Republicans control  redistricting in Pennsylvania,
下次選舉我們會失去眾議院
we lose the House next election,
你們每個人  也會失去委員會主席的席位
and all of you  lose your committee chairmanships.
這對彼得的競選至關重要
This is a feather that we need in Peter's hat.
如果這提案沒通過  會危及他當選的機會
A loss on this bill  endangers his chance ofwinning,
我們也要努力維持多數席位
and we are fighting to keep our majority here.
有其他疑問嗎？
Any other concerns?
明天下午4點前  把第一輪票數給我
I want a first vote count  by 4:00 tomorrow afternoon.
多謝各位
Thank you all very much.
真趕，三天內要去22個點
It's brutal. Twenty-two stops in three days.
- 要常在巴士上睡覺  - 沒空睡覺
-It's a lot of sleeping on the bus.  -No sleeping.
我只能在那巴士上工作
That bus is the only place  I can get work done.
法蘭斯在1998年  坐巴士展開長途巡迴
You know, Francis did a big bus tour in 1998,
那台巴士煞車失靈  衝下山坡
and the bus lost its brakes going down a hill
掉入煙草田里
and we landed in a tobacco field.
他走下巴士，敲農夫的門
He gets out of the car,  knocks on the farmer's door,
開了張支票賠償作物損失
writes a check for all the damaged crops,
然後借他的小卡車  才不致錯過下一個活動
and then borrows his pickup  so he doesn't miss the next event.
其實滿好玩的
And it was actually fun.
他開車，我坐前座  所有人員坐在平板拖車上
He was driving. I was shotgun,  and they had the whole staff in the flatbed.
結果還提早十分鐘到場
We actually got there 10 minutes early.
我想我應該在這裏拉票
I think I should be here  to help drum up votes.
小心，很燙
Careful, sir. It's very hot.
你跟副總統要上全國新聞
Look, you and the Vice President  are gonna get national coverage.
那會幫我們拉到票數
That's gonna help us with the count.
我找過他，可是一直沒回音
I reached out to him.  He never got back to me.
我甚至不知道他是否瞭解  提案的勸說重點
I don't know if he even knows  the talking points about the bill.
我覺得吉姆不想去
I don't think Jim wants to go.
他只是回總統和我的人情
He's doing it as a favor  to the President and l,
所以他不知道勸說重點  也沒關係
so it doesn't matter if he doesn't know  the talking points.
大家想看到他親民的樣子  知道嗎？
People wanna see him be folksy, you know?
順著他，讓他有點…
So just humor him.  Show him some degree of...
天啊
Oh, my God.
- 沒事吧？  - 不是故意的
-Are you okay?  -lt was an accident.
我們該走了，真抱歉
Okay, it's time for us to go. I'm so sorry.
沒關係，用冷水沖沖就好了
It's all right.  I just need to run it under some cold water.
不騙你，我厭惡小孩
I'm not going to lie. I despise children.
就是這樣
There. I've said it.
你不能在這裏胡鬧
You can't act like that in here.
- 你長大了  - 我知道
-You have to be a big boy.  -I know.
彼得，我們真的該走了
Peter, we really need to get going.
會議超時  已經讓我們錯過班機了
We've already missed one flight  because the meeting went over.
我改訂9點25分那班，可是…
I booked us another one at 9:25, but...
我們得先送小孩上學
We have to drop the kids off at school.
時間會很趕
It's going to be really tight.
如果錯過這班  第一個活動就要取消
If we miss this plane,  we have to cancel our first event.
南茜，你能帶他們去嗎？
Nancy, can you take them?
我要為次黨團的午餐匯報  準備資料
I've gotta get packets ready  for the lunchtime subcaucuses.
彼得，我愛莫能助  20分鐘後要和綠色和平開會
Peter, I'd do it, but we have a meeting  with Greenpeace in 20 minutes.
要取得他們的提案評價
I gotta get their rating on the bill.
學校在哪？
Where's their school?
康乃狄克街和Q街
Connecticut and Q.
- 我可以帶他們去  - 真的？
-Oh, I can take them.  -You sure?
我去辦公室剛好順路
Yes. It's on the way to my office.
這個分水嶺法案再次證明
This Watershed Act proves that once again
民主黨內充斥著  反資本主義的態度
the anti-capitalist agenda is alive and well  in the Democratic party.
我來讓大家看看真相
Let me show you what's really going on.
民主黨員太注重社會科學
Here are the Democrats  eating up all of their soft science,
被那些環保狂熱分子…
"organically homegrown" propaganda
「有機種植」的教條所洗腦
that the eco-fanatics are force-feeding them.
這裏呢，在那些王八蛋的後面
And over here,  at the tail-end of all those jackasses,
是中產階級的美國人
are middle-class Americans.
他們只想勤奮工作
People who just want to work hard
仰賴鑽井業的就業機會
and rely on jobs in the drilling industry.
彼得魯索要選州長？
各位，虛偽的是
And what about the hypocrisy, folks?
彼得魯索還有膽向我們說教  說我們污染河流
Does Peter Russo honestly have the gall  to lecture us on the purity of our rivers,
而多年來他卻一直  以藥品在污染自己？
when he has been polluting himself  with chemicals for years?
他不只是在吃草，他在哈草
He's not just been eating grass,  he's been smoking it.
六年來他推動過的  大型提案只有這一個
It's the only major bill  he's sponsored in six years.
我知道，但他們已經上全國新聞  還有什麼好報導？
I know, but they already have national  coverage. What's the angle?
如果提案不通過
If it doesn't pass,
我想他會  失去造船工業會的支持
I think he'll lose support  from the Shipbuilders' Association.
失去支持又怎樣  觀眾又不會關心
So they lose support. It's not that juicy.
他們在他費城的競選活動中  有舉足輕重的地位
They're a huge part of  his get-out-the-vote effort in Philly.
聽起來好像無聊的棒球內幕
It sounds like inside baseball.
若能拿到票數就不是
Not if I get the vote count.
準確的票數，沒人拿得到
Black and white numbers. Nobody has that.
可是我打電話給競選辦公室時  他們不給我消息
But when I called the campaign,  they stone-walled me.
黨鞭辦公室也是
Same thing at the Whip's office.
你認識那邊的人嗎？  法蘭斯辦公室？
Do you know anyone over there?  In Underwood's office?
不認識
No, I don't.
幕僚也不認識？
Nobody on staff?
你既然弄得到魯索的檔案  應該很有辦法
I just figured  because you gave me the Russo profile.
那不是從那邊來的
No, that didn't come from them.
可是競選活動是安德沃安排的
But Underwood organized the campaign.
抱歉，我不認識那邊的人
I'm sorry. I don't know anybody there.
好吧
Okay.
是我，我想爆點內幕
Hey, it's me.  I just wanted to fill you in on something.
我應該10點會回家，在家見面
I should be back home at 10:00.  Meet me there.
- 這個是莎拉做的  - 是青蛙
-Sarah made this one.  -It's a frog.
這個是我做的，你猜是什麼？
And I made this one.  Can you guess what it is?
龍蝦？
A lobster?
不是，是蠍子，送你  因為你也送過我們
No. It's a scorpion. They're for you.  For the ones you gave us.
好漂亮
They're beautiful.
也許你應該帶去學校吧？
But maybe you should  bring them to school, no?
上課時拿出來解說，或送給朋友？
For show-and-tell?  Or give them to your friends.
不要，其他小孩會嘲笑我們
No. The other kids will just make fun of us.
為什麼？
Why?
學校裏每個人都恨我們
Everybody hates us at school.
他們說爸是毒蟲  我們是毒蟲小孩
They say Dad's a crackhead  and that we're crack babies.
我上網查「毒蟲小孩」的圖片  我才不像那樣
I looked up "crack baby" on the computer.  I don't look like that.
他們說爸會吸毒過量死掉  就像艾美懷斯
You know, they say Dad's gonna OD  like Amy Winehouse.
你們告訴他們  爸爸已經不再做那種事了
Well, you tell them that your dad  doesn't do that kind of thing anymore, right?
我們有啊，可是他們不相信
Yeah, we do, but they don't believe us.
你們有去找老師嗎？
Did you try going to the teachers?
不行，大家會更恨我們
We can't do that.  Everyone would just hate us even more.
你不能擔心別人怎麼想，對吧？
Well, you can't worry about  what other people think, right?
如果爸不競選州長就好了
I wish Dad wasn't running for governor.
- 你來過艾倫鎮嗎？  - 沒有
-You ever been to Allentown before?  -I have not.
感覺如何？
What do you think?
停車比紐約容易
Compared to New York, the parking is easier.
要找能吃的貝果卻不容易
Finding a decent bagel, not so much.
我們的乳酪起司是他們沒有的
We'd make up for it with the cream cheese.
- 開始吧？  - 你好了就開始
-Shall we?  -Ready when you are.
你的分水嶺法案
Your Watershed Bill.
你讓共和黨人  石油天然氣產業都很不爽…
You've ticked off the Republicans, oil, gas...
做正當的事  有時總會激怒一些人
Sometimes you gotta  upset a few people to do the right thing.
不只是一些人，有一籮筐的人  希望你的提案不通過
Not just a few. There's a sizable coalition  that wants to see your bill fail,
包括你自己黨內的環保人士
including environmentalists  from your own party
- 覺得提案做得不夠  - 我們要能通過的提案
-who don't think the bill does enough.  -We wanted a passable bill.
所以我們採取折衷方案…
That's why we aimed for a middle ground...
你真的關心德拉瓦河嗎？
Do you actually care  about the Delaware River?
如果不關心，我不會支持立法
I don't sponsor legislation I don't care about.
在此之前，你沒有支持任何立法
Until recently, you hadn't sponsored  any legislation at all.
我在國會…
I spent my time in Congress
專注於對我選區選民重要的事務
focusing on things  that were important to my constituents.
造船廠
The shipyard.
我已經盡量拖延關閉
Kept it open as long as I could.
好，那是一件事，其他的呢？
Okay. That's one thing. What are the others?
我很願意向你列出我在國會  所做過的所有事項
I'd love to provide you a list of  all the things I've done in Congress,
不過只有15分鐘…
but we've got 15 minutes...
你的對手說你沒有作為  是因為貪飲威士忌
Your opponent has linked your inactivity  to your fondness for single-malts.
我對我的過去毫不隱瞞
I've been very open about my past,
我也盡全力  以負責任的態度完全戒酒
and I've done everything I can to overcome it  in a responsible, permanent way.
我喜歡伏特加，不是威士忌  你沒有查清楚
And I preferred vodka to scotch.  You should get your facts straight.
你是否只是想藉著  分水嶺法案出出風頭
Is your Watershed Act  just a ploy to jump into the spotlight
好幫助你競選州長？
and pad your transcript  while you apply for governor school?
這個法案能提供金錢  和就業機會
It's real money. It's real jobs.
德拉瓦河50年來  污染程度大幅降低
And when the Delaware River  is less polluted than it's been in 50 years,
杯子裏的水就來自那條河  看看多清澈
it's holding up a real glass of its water  and seeing how clear it is.
我的巴士巡迴目的就在此
That's what my bus tour is about.
- 副總統稍晚會加入？  - 對
-The Vice President is joining you later?  -Correct.
他為什麼等這麼久  才表態支持你？
Why has it taken him  this long to endorse you?
以前他覺得我不值得支持
He didn't think I was worth it.
後來他聽說我接受  《紐約時報》一對一專訪
But then he heard I had a one-on-one  with The New York Times,
忽然他就同意支持了
and, boom, he was on board.
這句我也許會刊出來
I might print that.
我多說，你少說
The more of my words, the fewer of yours,
這對你我都好
the better off we'll both be.
議員，要不是你這人  喜歡跟自己過不去
If I didn't think you were such a liability  to yourself, Congressman,
我也許會喜歡你
I might even like you.
若你的發行量  有《華爾街日報》那麼高
Ifyour circulation was as high  as The Wall Street Journal,
我也許也會喜歡你
I might like you back.
問吧，下一個問題
Hit me. Next question.
我得拼了，法蘭
I have to put up a fight, Frank.
告訴他們是在浪費金錢
Tell them they're wasting their money.
- 這會通過的  - 你確定？
-It's gonna pass.  -Are you sure?
我哪次錯估了選票？
When was the last time I got a count wrong?
如果你那麼確定  就不會想盡辦法要拉攏我們
If you were certain, you wouldn't  be trying to neutralize us.
善可工業對我們一直很好
Well, SanCorp has been good to me.
我只是想幫你  和他們一個忙，瑞米
I'm just trying to do you  and them a favor, Remy.
那一開始為何要提議立法？
Then why propose the legislation  in the first place?
你一定知道會反對
You must've known they would oppose it.
法規只有最低限制
The regulatory restrictions are minimal.
有更大的仗要打，法蘭
There's a bigger battle here, Frank.
善可工業反對任何規範提議
SanCorp is against  any step toward regulation,
無論有多小
no matter how small.
魯索選錯了立場
Russo's planted his feet  on the wrong side of the fence.
你要給他的對手多少？
How much are you giving his opponent?
去查查聯邦選委會檔案
Check the FEC filings.
你實際上要給多少？
How much are you actually giving?
這個行業產值高達一百億  法蘭，我們有的是錢
It's a $10 billion industry, Frank.  There's money to spend.
如果民主黨在賓州失利  你知道下場如何
If the Democrats lose Pennsylvania,  you know what that means.
我們不希望你失去領袖地位  但要看你自己，不是我們
We don't want you to lose leadership,  but that's up to you, not us.
你跟共和黨的關係…
You don't have the same kind  of relationship with the Republicans
不比我們
that you have with me.
那我們就要適應
Then we'll adapt.
我們都有票要數，祝你好運
We both have votes to count. Good luck.
你去告訴善可工業  他們的做法不明智
You tell SanCorp they're being foolish.
我不會說的
I'm not gonna do that.
那就是你不明智
Well, then, you're being foolish.
拜託，法蘭  我只是公事公辦
Come on, Frank.  Let's not make this personal.
善可工業勢力強大  我無法抗衡
I can't compete with SanCorp's war chest.
我只能不按牌理出牌
My only option is asymmetrical.
像樹林裏的狙擊手一樣  把對手一個個揪出來
To pick off the opposition one by one  like a sniper in the woods.
總有一天  我會把目標對準瑞米
There will come a time  to put Remy in my crosshairs,
但現在還不是時候
but not right now.
我們蓋弗尼有句俗話
As we used to say in Gaffney,
「絕不打嚼煙草的人」
"Never slap a man  while he's chewing tobacco."
「重新開始！」
支持魯索競選州長
議員，你好嗎？
Congressman, how are you?
我非常感謝你在百忙中抽空…
I deeply appreciate you  taking the time out of your schedule...
漢克，我餓死了
Hank, I need to eat.
能不能快送上總匯三明治  多加點培根
See if you can rustle up  a club sandwich, extra bacon.
媽的
Fuck me.
又吃泰國菜
Thai cuisine again.
綠咖哩是你的  另一個綠咖哩是我的
The green curry is for you,  and the other green curry is for me.
我正要出去
I was actually just on my way out.
我幫你買了晚餐  你一定要吃
I bought you dinner. You have to eat it.
至少你要看我吃我的晚餐
Or at the very least,  you have to watch me eat mine.
我約了人，快遲到了
I'm gonna be late to meet someone.
誰？約會嗎？
Who? Like, a date?
朋友
A friend.
那個常爆料給你的神秘炮友嗎？
The mysterious fuck-buddy  who you get all of your stories from?
放輕鬆點，我是開玩笑的
Lighten up. I was just teasing.
反正我也不會指責你  我們都幹過這種事
Not that I would judge. We've all done it.
以前我為了搶新聞  什麼骯髒事沒做過
I used to suck, screw and jerk  anything that moved just to get a story.
真的？有誰？
Really? Like who?
- 你想聽八卦嗎？  - 沒有，只是…
-You want dish?  -No. It's just...
班史洛德競選參議員時的  通訊總監
The Comm Director  on Ben Schroeder's Senate race.
國防部辦事員
A staffer in the Defense Department.
我自己的白宮助理
My very own White House intern.
他的嘴巴很飢渴  而且很會八卦
He was a real blabbermouth  when he wasn't eating me out.
我甚至跟一個議員有過一腿
And I even had a fling with a Congressman.
哪一個？
Which one?
你告訴我，我就告訴你
You tell me yours, and I'll tell you mine.
我沒有做過這種事
I've never been with any.
少來，你是個正妹
Oh, come on. You're hot.
你說沒有人對你示好？
You're telling me  that none of them have come on to you?
我其實還沒進入那個圈子
I haven't really been in those circles.
你現在進入了
You are now.
我大概沒有散發那種魅力
I guess I don't really give off that vibe.
騷貨的魅力？
You mean the slut vibe?
我已經不做那種事了
Look, I don't do that shit anymore.
因為事情一傳開  我就到處碰壁
'Cause once word got out,  it was like I hit a wall,
沒有人認真看待我
and nobody took me seriously.
所以我勸你  以職場策略而言
So, a piece of advice,  as far as career strategies go,
出賣身體來獲取地位  是不值得的
it's not worth fucking your way to the middle.
你用筷子還是叉子？
Chopsticks or fork?
法蘭安德沃
如果你要走  我就把兩份吃掉
Look, if you go,  I am gonna have to eat both of these,
我會很不爽
and that is not cool.
我跟你一起吃
No. I'll eat with you.
好
Good.
副總統吉姆馬修  在東賓州的州長空缺席位
Things have gotten underway in Eastern  Pennsylvania for the governor's seat left
競選活動已展開
vacant there by Vice President Jim Matthews.
親民的副總統  即賓州前任州長
After a political career that has lasted  42 years so far,
在從政42年後
the genial Vice President and  the former Pennsylvania Governor,
面對他在新職位上  最關鍵的工作
faces the most critical task of his  new electoral life
就是在他前往華府之際  幫助他的家鄉選出新州長
helping his home state fill the vacancy of  his departure from Washington.
然而，馬修似乎不太願意  交棒給彼得魯索
However, Matthews seems reluctant to  hand over the spotlight to Peter Russo.
會晚30分鐘左右
我不等人的
回家，米契
Back home, Meechum.
是的
Sir.
法蘭斯…
Francis...
你的手還好嗎？
How's your hand?
好
Fine.
- 要不要換繃帶？  - 等等
-You should change the bandage, no?  -Later.
- 我以為你會晚點回來  - 沒有
-I thought you were gonna be out late.  -No.
- 你好像有點生氣  - 沒有
-You seem upset.  -I'm not.
- 怎麼了？  - 沒事
-What happened?  -Nothing.
你就不能多說兩個字嗎？
Can I get more than two words out of you?
我只想放鬆一下
I'm just trying to relax.
克萊兒，我愛你
Claire, I love you.
我也愛你
I love you too.
難道喬伊以為我會  無所事事地等她來嗎？
Did Zoe expect me  to twiddle my thumbs until her arrival?
她大概搞錯了  以為她的時間跟我的一樣寶貴
Perhaps she's making the mistake  thinking her time is as valuable as mine.
有人以為自己接近權力  就表示擁有權力
Proximity to power deludes some  into believing they wield it.
我會讓他們還沒開始  就打消這種念頭
I put an end to that sort of thinking  before it begins.
如果沒記錯的話  我上次來泰納斯維爾時
And if I'm not mistaken,  the last time I was in Tannersville,
巴狄卡克倫把我拉到一旁  告訴我我在浪費時間
Buddy Corcharan pulled me aside  and told me I was wasting my time,
因為共和黨  即將在門羅郡大獲全勝
because the Republicans were gonna  sweep Monroe County in a landslide.
結果我在門羅郡大獲全勝
Well, Buddy had to eat his hat  and both his shoes
讓巴狄跌破眼鏡，還跌破皮鞋
when I won the county in a landslide.
告訴你們，他的腳掌很大
And let me tell you, that man has big feet
頭更大，跌破頭更慘
and an even bigger head,  so that was quite a meal.
我爸爸以前告訴我一個故事
My daddy used to  tell me a story about people
說在母雞生蛋前  不要先數雞蛋
who count their chickens  before they hatched.
不過老實說
Although, to be fair,
他大概不知道自己在說什麼
he probably didn't know  what he was talking about,
因為他是在匹茲堡長大的
because he grew up in Pittsburgh.
我在家附近根本沒看過母雞
And I certainly never saw  a hen around my house,
除非把我媽算進去
unless you count my mother.
- 要不要我出面？  - 可是說真的…
-Do you want me to do something?  -But, seriously, folks...
- 沒關係，讓他說  - …我很喜歡這個鎮
-No. Let him talk.  -...I do love this town.
不知道他到底會不會介紹你
I don't know if he's ever  going to introduce you.
給他一點時間吧
He will. Just give him time.
已經一個鐘頭了
It's been an hour.
我們十分鐘前就應該動身  前往卡本戴爾了
We were supposed to leave for Carbondale  10 minutes ago.
我不能打斷他，他是副總統
I can't interrupt him. He's the Vice President.
我們不是在賓氏樹林的邊緣
We're not on the edge of Penn's Woods.
我們需要分水嶺法案的  經濟開發流程圖
We need economic development flowcharts  for the Watershed Bill
送去泰利沃麥克辦公室
sent over to Terry Womack's office.
- 打印20份出來  - 我馬上去做
-Hard copies, 20 of them.  -I'll do it right away.
瑞秋一切都好嗎？
How's everything going with Rachel?
我想她心情不太好
I think she's a little down in the dumps.
她上周找到服務生的工作  後來被解雇了
She got a waitressing job last week,  and then they let her go.
- 為什麼？  - 她不願說
-Why?  -She wouldn't tell me.
她只說她老闆很低級
All she said was her boss was a creep.
30分鐘前，我接到喬伊的簡訊
Thirty minutes ago,  I received a text from Zoe.
顯然她想要道歉
She intends to apologize, no doubt.
她要當面贖罪，我尊重她
I respect that she wants to atone in person,
即使花了她16小時  才鼓起勇氣
even though it's taken her over 16 hours  to build up the courage.
珍妮史柯斯基  在挖彼得魯索的新聞
Janine Skorsky is digging into Peter Russo.
哪方面的事？
What in particular?
造船工業會
The Shipbuilder's Association.
她想報導什麼？
She have an angle?
分水嶺法案  是他們失業的安慰獎
The Watershed Bill is a consolation prize  for them losing their jobs.
這個看法不是空穴來風
That's not an unfair assessment.
她覺得如果提案不通過  他們就不會支持他
She thinks if the bill fails to pass,  they'll withdraw support.
這樣想不是沒有道理
Not unfair speculation.
我知道你非常努力在助選
Well, I know how hard  you've been working on his campaign,
所以我先爆料給你
so I wanted to give you a heads up.
如果她繼續挖別的新聞  就告訴我
Well, let me know if she expands her inquiry.
挖什麼新聞？
Into what?
你覺得值得透露的新聞
Anything you deem worth telling.
要不要用餌來引誘她？
Well, can I throw her a bone?
如果我有消息給她  她也許會多說一點
She might be more talkative  if I have information for her.
- 哪種餌？  - 提案的票數
-What sort of bone?  -The vote count for the bill.
我還沒拿到票數
I don't have a vote count yet.
今天下午  初步票數結果應該會出來
Should have a preliminary one  this afternoon.
會告訴我嗎？
You'll let me know?
一有確切消息就告訴你
As soon as I have something solid.
還有一件事
There's one more thing.
對於昨晚…
About last night...
不用道歉
No need to apologize.
我相信你有非常好的理由
I'm sure you had a very good reason.
沒錯
I do.
我覺得我們不該繼續下去
I think we should end it.
不是公事，我是說另一件事
Not professionally, the other thing.
為何選現在？
Why now?
我們在工作上合作愉快
We have a really good working relationship.
我不想把事情搞複雜
I don't wanna overcomplicate that.
好
All right.
- 你同意？  - 完全同意
-You're okay with it?  -Completely.
結束了
It's over.
我們之間的安排還是照舊？
And it won't change things  in terms of our arrangement?
拜託，我不會因為別人  做成熟決定就懲罰他們
Oh, please. I don't punish people  for making adult decisions.
謝謝你，法蘭斯
Thank you, Francis.
她不過是我雷達上  一個微弱的小點
She was never more  than a faint blip on my radar.
我們互相利用
We've served each other's purpose.
如果她想要長大
If she wants to be an adult,
就讓她看看自己離巢  還能不能飛
Iet her see how she can fly  once she leaves the nest.
- 克萊兒，你好  - 凱薩琳
-Claire. Hi.  -Catherine.
謝謝你抽空見我
Thank you for fitting me in.
對於你和法蘭  我一定抽得出空來
I can always find time for you and Frank.
我來這裏是因為
Well, the reason I'm here
淨水創權有一大批  濾水器被扣在南蘇丹
is the CWl has a large shipment of  water filters stuck in South Sudan,
已經存放四個月
and they've been in storage  for the past four months,
放在那裏不能動，蘇丹政府…
just sitting there,  and the Sudanese government...
不能從海關運送出來
Won't release the shipments  through customs.
我的代理人把近況告訴我了
My deputy briefed me on the latest.
我知道法蘭斯  不久前和你談過這件事
Right. And I know that Francis  spoke to you about this not too long ago,
但最近國務院一直沒有消息
but lately we haven't heard much  from the State Department,
你能不能幫忙
so I was wondering if you could help.
我們盡力了，克萊兒  我找最能幹的人員來處理
We've done our best, Claire.  I put my top people on this.
蘇丹就是沒有回應
The Sudanese are just not responding.
還有別的辦法嗎？
Well, is there anything else we can do?
有價值20多萬元的器材
There's over $200,000 worth of equipment.
沒辦法，我知道這對你很重要
I wish I could.  I know how important this is to you,
可是我們即將中斷外交關係
but we're about to cut off diplomatic ties.
這是總統直接下的指令
It's a directive straight from the President.
我們無法再對他們  侵犯人權的作為坐視不顧
We can't ignore  their human rights violations anymore.
私底下的管道呢？
What about back channels?
一旦中斷關係
Well, once we cut ties,
就無法以官方或非官方的方式  和他們的政府連絡
I can't contact their government  officially or unofficially.
能幫我牽個線嗎？
Well, is there someone  you could put me in touch with?
很抱歉，克萊兒
I'm sorry, Claire.
我無能為力
My hands are tied.
為了你和法蘭  我會上山下海，但我盡力了
I would move mountains for you and Frank,  but I've done all I can.
當然
Of course.
- 很高興見到你  - 我也是
-Okay. Good to see you.  -You too.
議員，你有個重大提案  本周稍晚即將進行投票
Congressman, you have a major bill  going to the floor later this week.
你有信心會通過嗎？
Are you optimistic it'll pass?
我很樂觀
I'm very optimistic.
德拉瓦河分水嶺法案
The Delaware River Watershed Act
不只保護本州  大面積的淡水資源
not only protects large portions of  the state's freshwater resources,
也能創造數千個就業機會
it also creates thousands of jobs.
我有信心，其他議員…
I'm confident that my colleagues on the Hill...
創造就業的方法只有一個  我在任內就做過
There's only one way to create jobs.  I did it during my administration.
就是為中小企業提供減稅
The answer is tax credits  for small businesses.
要鼓勵白手起家的創業人士
You've got to encourage  self-starting entrepreneurs
創立新公司、僱用員工…
to start new ventures, hire employees...
但是特別提到分水嶺法案…
But specifically, about the Watershed Act...
答案就是中小企業  其他一切只是表面工夫
Small businesses, that's the solution.  Everything else is window dressing.
非常謝謝
Thank you all very much.
謝謝
Thank you.
晚安，副總統
Good night, Mr. Vice President.
- 你好  - 我必須和馬修談談
-Hello.  -I need to talk about Matthews.
我讀了記者的報告  他沒幫上什麼忙，對吧？
Yes. I've read the press reports.  He's not being very helpful, is he?
他在幫倒忙
No, he's doing more harm than good.
我要叫他走
I want to ask him to leave.
這新聞見報可就不好了
Well, that wouldn't make  for a very good story.
至少不會變成由他來  主導這趟巴士巡迴
It's better than him  torpedoing the whole bus tour.
你和他談過嗎？
Have you tried to talk to him?
還沒，我想先聽你的意見
No, I wanted to ask your advice first.
也許有辦法  能讓他留在巴士巡迴中
Well, maybe there's a way  to keep him on the tour
同時激發他的支持
and inspire his support.
我們的基本看法不同
We have fundamentally different views.
你無法改變他的意識形態
Well, look, you're not going to  be able to change his ideology,
但要深入瞭解
but dig deeper.
吉姆是個很自豪的人  要利用他自豪的態度
Jim is a proud man. Tap into that pride.
我只希望他走
I just wish he was gone.
你自己決定吧
Well, you do whatever you think best.
但是無論決定如何  要果斷和堅定自己的立場
But whatever it is you decide,  be firm and stand up for yourself.
這樣至少他會有所反應
He'll respond to that at least.
如果有什麼需要，打電話給我
And call me back if you need anything.
他給你的理由是什麼？  你搞砸了嗎？
What was the reason he gave you?  Were you messing up?
沒有，領班說我做得很好
No. The head waiter said  I was doing a really good job.
他還在我第二天上班  就給我自己的桌子
He even started letting me  take my own tables on the second day.
經理呢…他叫什麼名字？
And the manager... What's his name?
李昂
Leon.
他對你毛手毛腳？
He propositioned you?
他叫我去他辦公室
Called me into his office,
說他雇不起新的員工
said couldn't afford  to start taking anyone new on,
兼職的也不行
even part-time.
他把手放我膝蓋上
Put his hand on my knee,
說他也許能破個例
said he might be able to make an exception.
他開始把手往我大腿上移動
So he starts sliding his hand up my thigh.
我站起來告訴他  我要回去工作
So I stood up and I tell him  I should get back to work.
他說：  「留下來」
He says, "Stay."
他把皮帶解開
He unbuckled his belt.
你就範了嗎？
Did you?
沒有，我走出辦公室  回到我的桌子
No, I walked out of the office  and got back to my tables.
隔天我回去上班  他叫我回家
Next day, I came into work,  told me to go home.
我被解雇了
I was fired.
告訴我那家餐館叫什麼
Tell me the name of the restaurant.
你提早回家了
You're home early.
我需要休息一下，早飯沒吃
I needed a breather.  I didn't have breakfast this morning.
可能一下就回去
I might head back in a little while.
票數怎樣？
The vote count?
鹿死誰手，要到最後才能分曉
It's going to come down  to the wire on this one.
我今天去找凱薩琳杜倫談
I spoke to Catherine Durant today.
她無法讓貨運出南蘇丹
She's unable to get the shipment  out of South Sudan.
我們要中斷所有外交關係
Yeah, we're cutting all diplomatic ties.
外交部已經劍拔弩張
Foreign Affairs is up in arms about it.
對，所以她說她無能為力
Yes. Which is why she can't lift a finger,  according to her.
反正她是那樣說的  你必須去和她談談
It's what she said, anyway.  Anyway, I need you to talk to her.
我談也沒用
I don't think that would make any difference.
- 她欠我們人情，法蘭斯  - 對，但人情有限
-I thought she owed us, Francis.  -She does, but there's limits.
她是國務卿  不能違反外交慣例
She's Secretary of State.  She can't break diplomatic protocol.
你能不能打個電話？
Well, can you make some calls?
她不行，我也沒轍  何況我在忙分水嶺提案的事
If she can't, I can't.  Plus I have to focus on the Watershed Bill.
我花自己的時間去幫你
I'm taking time out of my schedule  to help you with that.
- 因為是你草擬的  - 因為是你要我做的
-Because you drafted it.  -Because you asked me.
我本來不想做的
I didn't want to do this.
我現在只是要你反過來  花點時間來幫我
All I'm asking is that you give me  a little bit of your time in return.
我就是沒辦法解決  你要我怎麼辦？
And how am I supposed to fix a problem  I can't fix?
瑞米呢？
What about Remy?
葛蘭頓希爾  在南蘇丹一定有連絡人
Glendon Hill must have contacts  in South Sudan.
他反對這個提案
He's fighting us on the vote.
這根本是兩碼子事
Those are two completely separate issues.
才不是，他幫了你的忙  現在我得回報
They are not. He does you a favor,  he hangs it over me.
所以你是說  我的目標不及你的重要
So what you're saying  is my goals are secondary to yours.
我不是這個意思
That is not what I'm saying.
他以前是你的屬下  我想你拉不下臉去求他
I think you don't want to go hat in hand  to somebody who used to work for you.
你別想一進門就訓我！
I will not be lectured to  the moment you walk in the door!
你要我打電話給凱薩琳  我也打了！
I called Catherine, as promised!
她無能為力不是我的問題  也不是我的錯！
Her inability to deliver  is not my problem or my fault!
我無法控制全球趨勢！
I cannot control changing global landscapes!
你不能咄咄逼人  要我答應做不到的事！
And I will not be cornered  into making promises I cannot deliver!
抱歉我對你大吼
I'm sorry I yelled.
我受到很大的壓力
I'm under a lot of pressure.
你說得沒錯，我沒想清楚
You're right, I didn't think it through.
我現在不能求助瑞米
I just can't go to Remy right now.
他挖走了我太多的人
He's poaching too many of my people.
我有兩個議員還沒表態
I've got two congressmen  who will not commit.
我還希望你去跟他們談談呢
I was hoping you might speak to them.
誰？
Who?
文德柏和亞柏斯
Vanderburgh and Abrams.
要我對他們說什麼？
What is it you want me to say to them?
他們很注重環保  認為這個提案做得不夠
They're big on the environment.  They don't think the bill goes far enough.
他們尊重你的意見
They respect your opinion.
我要你一步步向他們  解釋整個提案
I wanted you  to walk them through the bill step-by-step.
讓他們放心  我必須得到他們表態支持
Put them at ease.  I need to get them in the yes column.
我明天會跟他們見面  跟他們來硬的
I meet with them tomorrow.  I'll deliver the bruises.
然後你再跟他們見面  動之以情
You meet with them later and patch them up.
軟硬兼施應該能奏效
That might just do the trick.
當然
Of course.
我好像把碗打破了
I think I broke the bowl.
我們透過石油股份  在那邊有些連絡人
We have contacts there  through our oil interests.
我需要政府干預
I'm going to need government intervention.
只要有政府，就有熟人
Wherever there's a government,  we know people.
即使只是政府的假象也行
Even when there's only  the illusion of a government.
你能幫忙嗎？
Will you help me?
我是願意
I'd like to.
不過這檔事恐怕代價不低
But for something like this,  I'm afraid there's a price tag.
淨水創權會把善可工業  列為環保企業
The CWl will endorse SanCorp  as eco-friendly.
他們可以在任何公關文件  或行銷材料上用我們的商標
They can use our logo on any PR  or marketing materials you want.
這還不夠
We'll need more than that.
他們願意為此捐出一百多萬元
They were willing to donate  over $1 million for that.
這些濾水器也不過值20萬元  應該很划算
These filters are only worth $200,000.  I'd say that's a bargain.
你拒絕了那個提議
You turned down that offer.
後來情況改觀了
Landscape has shifted since then.
- 分水嶺提案？  - 對
-The Watershed Bill?  -That's right.
你希望修改它？
You want it amended?
我希望你讓整個提案被否決
I want you to kill it, the whole thing.
瑞米，淨水創權已經  公開支持這個提案
CWl has publicly backed the bill, Remy.
你公開支持，那是你的問題
What you do publicly is your concern.
各位請坐
Gentlemen. Please, have a seat.
自從上次談過以後  你們有人改變主意嗎？
So, have either of you changed your mind  since we last spoke?
我們還沒做決定，法蘭
We're still undecided, Frank.
傾向哪一方？
Leaning one way or the other?
如果國會要撥出兩億五千萬元
If Congress is going to allocate  $250 million dollars,
我們要確定這筆錢…
we want to make sure it goes towards a bill
能保護…
that does more to protect the...
這些都談過了  我知道你們的顧慮
We've been through all that.  I know your concerns.
如果保護標準不改變
So if the protection standards don't change,
我們寧願見到那筆錢  更有效花在其他地方
we would rather see that money  spent more effectively elsewhere.
聽起來你們傾向不支持
That sounds like you're both leaning no.
我們的訴求一直很清楚
We've been very clear  about what we're asking.
好
Okay.
這是你，亞柏斯
This is you, Abrams.
這是你，文德柏
And this is you, Vanderburgh.
這裏呢
And over here
是民主黨黨團的多數
is the majority of the Democratic Caucus.
你們獨自在那裏
See, you're over there all by your lonesome.
你們不介意孤軍奮戰
Now, you don't mind being the black sheep.
你們是自由派中的自由派
You're the liberal wing of the liberal wing.
平常你們怎麼投票都行  反正提案會通過
Most of the time you can vote what you want,  we still pass things anyway.
但是這次不同
But this time it does matter.
你們沒有考慮到
And what the two of you  aren't taking into account
在書桌這邊和這邊的中間
is between this end of the desk  and this end of the desk,
有我
is me.
我要跟你們說  我對所有議員說的話
Now, I'm going to say to you  what I say to every congressman
他們也坐過這個位置
that sits where you're sitting now.
依照選區意願投票  依照良心來投票
Vote your district. Vote your conscience.
別讓我感到意外
Don't surprise me.
最重要的一點還是
And the most important one of those
別讓我感到意外
is don't surprise me.
你們明天要跟我老婆見面
Now, you're both to meet  with my wife tomorrow.
你們要聽她把話說完
And you're to hear her out.
她會就你們的疑慮  逐一向你們解釋
She will go through your concerns  point-by-point.
我確信，和她談過以後
And I am certain after that
你們兩位會做出正確的決定
that the two of you  will make the right decision.
你們可以走了
This is the part where you leave.
我發現，滿腔熱血的人
I have often found that bleeding hearts
反而往往害怕自己的血
have an ironic fear of their own blood.
見到一滴就嚇昏過去
One drop and they seize up.
不過，伸出援手按摩一下  把他們救醒之後
But offer them a caring hand  and massage them back to life
他們馬上就會開始  跟著你的步伐走
and they soon start  beating to the right drum.
你好
Hello.
我剛跟亞柏斯和文德柏談了
I've just spoken to Abrams and Vanderburgh.
讓他們今晚輾轉反側
Let them toss and turn tonight,
明天就任你擺佈
but they're all yours tomorrow.
我會跟他們的辦公室安排時間
I'll reach out to their offices and set a time.
謝謝你，克萊兒
Thank you, Claire.
不謝，我盡量幫忙
Of course. Whatever I can do to help.
先生，請慢用
Here you go, sir. Enjoy.
對不起，我的牛排裏有根頭髮
Excuse me. There's a hair on my steak.
對不起，在哪裏？
I am so sorry, sir. Where?
就在那裏
Right there.
我沒看到
I don't see it.
你是說我瞎了眼嗎？
Are you telling me I'm blind?
不是，對不起，我去請廚房…
No, sir. I'm so sorry. I'll have the kitchen...
- 你叫什麼名字？  - 史蒂芬妮
-What's your name?  -Stephanie.
你把盤子留下，史蒂芬妮  我想和經理談談
You can leave the plate, Stephanie.  I'd like to talk to the manager.
好，我去找他
Yes, sir. I'll go get him.
謝謝
Thank you.
先生，晚安
Good evening, sir.
史蒂芬妮說你的盤子裏有頭髮
Stephanie tells me  there was a hair on your plate.
沒有
No.
沒有頭髮  你叫李昂，對吧？
There wasn't any hair.  Leon, right? That's your name?
對
Yes.
史蒂芬妮很正，對吧？
Stephanie is a hot little number, isn't she?
前凸後翹
Nice ass.
你在雇她之前還是之後  叫她幫你吹喇叭？
Did you make her blow you  before or after you hired her?
先生，請你離開
Sir, I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
- 坐，李昂  - 先生，我要你離開
-Sit down, Leon.  -Sir, I want you to go.
- 我說坐下  - 不然我就叫警察了
-I said sit.  -Don't make me call the police.
告訴你
I'll tell you what.
你叫警察，我就叫移民局
You call the police,  I'll call the Department of lmmigration
說你僱用四個黑工在廚房工作
about the four undocumented employees  you have working in the kitchen.
要重罰，李昂
A felony, Leon.
我可能也會提到  你的女朋友、她媽媽和她阿姨
And I might also mention your girlfriend,  her mother, and her aunt
也都沒有身份  住在你付錢的公寓裏
who are also undocumented  and living in an apartment you pay for.
你會坐牢，她們會被軀逐出境
Prison time for you, deportation for them.
那就慘了，對吧？
Not a pretty picture, is it?
我們來談談瑞秋珀斯納
Let's talk about Rachel Posner.
票數多接近？
How close is it?
我今天應該會得到最後兩票
I should have the last two votes  I need committed today.
我只想確定沒有人改變主意
I just want to make sure  no one changes their mind.
這個節骨眼最好不要  牽扯到環保問題
I'd prefer not to get embroiled  in environmental issues at this time.
但也能創造就業機會
But it's also a jobs creation package.
提案反對石油和天然氣
It's antagonizing oil and gas.
我們在教育投資這麼多  沒有本錢和他們作對
We can't afford that sort of battle  after all the capital we spent on education.
我只希望你公開表態支持
All I need is one public statement of support.
我辦不到  不如你明天帶琳達去吧？
I won't do that.  How about you take Linda tomorrow?
在你辦公室幫她準備好
You set her up in your offices.
需要開會或打電話催票
Any meetings or calls  you might need to whip up votes,
她在那邊幫你
you've got her there.
我沒空花一整天時間  在國會進行遊說
Well, I can't afford to spend a whole day  lobbying on the Hill.
你有代理人
Well, you've got deputies.
沒錯
Yes, I do.
只差十條街  你也無法管理他們？
Well, you're telling me  you can't manage them from 10 blocks away?
當然可以
Of course I can, sir.
如果太困難的話…
Look, if it's too difficult...
不會的，我們會幫助你，法蘭  對吧，琳達？
No, no, no. We'll help you out, Frank.  Won't we, Linda?
我先走一步
Yes. If you'll just excuse me,
我要重新安排時間表
I have a few things to rearrange  on my schedule.
還有什麼事，法蘭？  告訴我柏許在搞什麼
What else, Frank?  Tell me what Birch is up to.
我知道我已經取消兩次
No, I know I've already canceled twice.
下周開始
They start next week.
甜心，我在想辦法
Sweetie, I'm trying to figure this out.
- 琳達  - 什麼事？
-Linda.  -Excuse me. Yes?
我只想謝謝你同意幫忙
I just wanted to thank you  for agreeing to pitch in,
- 我知道你已經忙不過來  - 別客氣，法蘭
-I know you have a full plate.  -Of course, Frank.
一切沒事吧？好像…
Is everything all right? It sounds like...
你要我明天什麼時候來？
Yes. What time do you want me  to come by tomorrow?
我們能談談嗎？
Can we talk?
我待會回電給你，好
Can I just call you back in one second?  I will call you. Yes.
琳達，很抱歉  讓總統強迫你處理這件事
Linda, I am so sorry  that the President has forced you into this.
不是我的本意
It was not my intention.
有需要的話  我可以跟國會談…
If you would like, I can talk to Congress...
不是，這是私事，沒關係
No, it's not that. It's a personal matter.  Don't worry.
什麼事？也許我能幫忙
Well, what is it? Maybe I can help.
我兒子沒有錄取史丹佛大學
Just, my son didn't get into Stanford.
我明天要和教務長見面
I was supposed to meet  with the Provost tomorrow
看能不能讓他回心轉意
to see if I could get him to change his mind.
我問總統能不能去  他原先答應了
I asked the President if I could go,  and he said yes,
但他一定忘記了
but he must have forgotten.
你應該去  總統一定會諒解的
You should go.  I'm sure the President will understand.
不行，我不會讓私事  影響到工作，法蘭
No, no. I don't let personal matters  get in the way of my job, Frank.
琳達，你不能讓生活停擺
Linda, you can't put your entire life on hold.
更不能連自己的兒子都不顧
And certainly not at the expense  of your own son.
我的確沒有顧到自己的兒子
Well, it has been at the expense of my son.
他沒被錄取是我的錯
It's my fault he didn't get in.
我一直忙助選，沒有空幫他
I was on the campaign  and I wasn't there for him.
他的成績變差，他的申請書…
His grades suffered. His application was...
我忽略了他，法蘭
I wasn't there, Frank.
我本來想  如果能和教務長面對面談…
But I figured if I could just meet  with the Provost face to face...
好，你明天就去史丹佛
Okay, look,  you are going to Stanford tomorrow.
如果你出現在我的辦公室  我不會讓你進去
If you show up at my office, I won't let you in,
所以連想都別想
so don't even consider it.
法蘭，總統要我…
Frank, the President wants me to be...
他不需要知道
He doesn't have to know.
我叫我的行政助理  幫你買張機票
I'm going to have one of my schedulers  buy you a ticket.
別擔心提案
The bill will be fine.
法蘭
Frank.
你不需要這樣做
You don't have to do this.
我們也許意見不同，琳達
We may have our disagreements, Linda,
不過這不表示  我們不能互相照顧
but that doesn't mean  we can't look out for each other.
你告訴他們你要來了
You tell them you're coming.
好，試試看
Okay. Give that a try.
試試看
Test, test, test.
喬伊，我是大衛  紐約的資深製作人
All right, Zoe. This is Dave,  the senior producer in New York.
- 再過四分鐘開始直播  - 好
-We'll go live in four minutes.  -Sounds good.
首先要談  國會秋季會期的議程
The first topic will be the Congressional  agenda for the fall session,
接著談期中議程
then we'll move on to the midterms,
最後談彼得魯索的  州長競選活動
then we'll wrap it up  with Peter Russo's race for governor
- 還有他的分水嶺法案  - 好
-and his Watershed Bill.  -Okay, great.
把你的麥克風關掉  最後30秒再打開
Taking you off mic until 30 out.
珍妮，我要談分水嶺法案
Hey, Janine, I have to talk  about the Watershed Bill.
你有單張資料嗎？
Do you have a one sheet?
有，等等
Yeah. Hold on.
謝謝
Thanks.
- 有票數的消息嗎？  - 還沒有
-Any word on the vote count?  -Still no luck.
我連絡眾議院所有民主黨議員  想湊出一個數字
I've called every Democrat in the House  to cobble together a number,
可是沒有人回電給我
but no one's getting back to me.
那我該說什麼？
So what can I say?
就說兩方票數接近  呈現拉鋸戰
That there's a lot in flux, and it'll be tight.
好，謝謝
Okay. Thanks.
不謝
Yeah. Sure thing.
法蘭斯，是我，請回電
Hey, Francis, it's me. Call me back.
什麼事？
Yes.
魯索議員找，他說有急事
Congressman Russo. He says it's urgent.
好
Fine.
副總統早
Good morning, sir.
我想談談巡迴的事
I'd like to talk about how the tour's going.
上巴士再談  不是11點有活動嗎？
Well, let's talk on the bus.  Don't we have an event at 11:00?
我們先談，再安排活動
There won't be any events until we talk.
你抓著麥克風不放
You're hijacking the microphone.
你一直和我唱反調
You're contradicting everything I say.
我們應該要推動分水嶺法案
We need to be promoting the Watershed Act.
我欣賞你直率的作風
Well, I appreciate your being so forthright.
但有一點我不欣賞
Let me tell you what I don't appreciate.
民主黨全委會  推出你來接替我的職位
The DNC is running a man  with zero track record,
你毫無建樹，又有酗酒前科
except for substance abuse, to fill my shoes.
我知道你不想來
I realize you don't want to be here, sir,
但你好像故意要  破壞我的競選活動
but it seems like you're deliberately trying  to sabotage my campaign.
雖然我心不甘情不願  但我還想拯救選情
Despite my better judgment,  I'm trying to save it.
我比你更瞭解本州的人，彼得
I know the people of this state  better than you, Peter.
他們不想聽分水嶺的事  他們想聽就業的事
They don't want to hear about watersheds.  They want to hear about jobs.
這周，他們兩者都聽
Well, this week, they need to hear both.
那我也許應該在講台上  默默站在你旁邊
Well, then, maybe I should just stand  quietly beside you at the podium
看你落選
and watch you lose.
- 你覺得我不會當選吧？  - 我不樂觀
-You don't think I can win, do you?  -I'm not optimistic.
你競選州長時，前兩次也落選
You lost the first two times  you ran for governor.
第三次，沒有人看好你
The third time,  nobody thought you had a chance.
到了九月，你還差15點  你用盡了資金
By September, you were 15 points down.  You were out of money.
必須把自己的房子拿去抵押  來付員工薪水
You had to mortgage your own house  just to keep your staff on payroll.
我的情況我自己知道
I'm well aware of what I did. I was there.
重點是，你勇往直前
My point is you kept going.
在20天內走遍67個郡
You hit 67 counties in less than 20 days,
證明了大家是錯的
and you proved everyone wrong.
無論你喜不喜歡  這次選票上印的是我的名字
Like it or not,  it's my name on the ticket this time,
我有這次機會  我會證明所有人都錯了
and I got the shot,  and I'm gonna prove everyone wrong,
就像你一樣，包括你在內
just like you did. Including you, sir.
我希望你支持我
I would like your support,
但是如果你不願意，也沒關係
but if you won't give it, fine.
這阻止不了我
It won't stop me.
你覺得我高興來這裏嗎？
You think it's easy for me to be here?
我做州長風頭正健，卻要離開
I left the Governor's mansion  right in my prime.
來做副總統？
To be what? Vice President.
我以為我陞官了
I thought that was a step up.
結果呢？我一點實權也沒有
But you know what?  I don't have a fucking shred of real influence.
我到處作秀像個吉祥物  這是我的家鄉
I'm trotted around like a goddamn mascot,  and this is my home state.
我向你提供實權
I'm offering you influence, sir.
我希望借重你的指導和專長
I'd like your guidance and your expertise.
不過如果你無法提供，那麼…
But if that's not on the table, then, well...
恕我直言，副總統先生  你應該回華府去
With all due respect, Mr. Vice President,  you should head back to Washington.
你的老公說得很直
Your husband was very explicit.
可以說是發出恐嚇
I would categorize it as a threat.
他究竟說了什麼？
What did he say exactly?
別讓他感到意外
Not to surprise him.
他不是也叫你們  依照選區意願和良心來投票嗎？
Didn't he also tell you  to vote your district and your conscience?
沒錯，不過這些對他來說  似乎遠遠不是重點
He did, but those seemed far lower  on his priority list.
如果你們有確切理由
Well, he would never fault you
來做你們認為正確的事  他是不會責怪你們的
ifyou had a compelling reason  to do what you think is right.
我有點迷糊了  你不是贊成這提案的嗎？
I'm confused. Aren't you for this bill?
淨水創權是公開支持提案
CWl is publicly for it.
私底下  我對提案的疑慮和你們一樣
Privately, I have my doubts  for the same reasons you do.
我以為你叫我們來  是要勸我們支持提案
I was under the impression that we were here  so you could persuade us to vote yes.
我沒有要勸你們支持  或反對任何事
I'm not trying to persuade you of anything.
我是要說
I will say this.
如果提案沒通過  也不是世界末日
If the bill fails, it's not the end of the world.
總是可以推動新法
We can always sponsor new legislation.
例如更嚴格的法規標準
You know, something  with stricter regulatory standards.
講清楚一點，你是說  我們投反對票也沒關係？
Just to be clear, you're telling us  you don't mind ifwe vote against the bill?
我只是說我老公所說的…
I'm simply saying what my husband would...
你們應該憑良心來投票
That you should vote your conscience.
情況如何？
How are we looking?
我們差一票
We're short a vote.
我剛跟克萊兒通了電話  文德柏和亞柏斯同意了
I just got off the phone with Claire.  Vanderburgh and Abrams are on board.
- 他們鐵定會投贊成票？  - 鐵定
-Those are definite yeses?  -Definite.
應該會通過
We should be good.
喂？
Yes?
我從昨天就一直在找你
I've been trying to reach you since yesterday.
我在忙著催票
Well, I've been a bit busy counting votes.
你說能給我一個數字
You said you'd have a number for me.
你應該跟我的新聞室連絡
Well, you should try my press office.
我有啊，他們不回我電話
I did. They won't return my calls.
官方的數字是非常接近
Well, the official word is it will be close.
我要的是非官方的數字
I'm trying to get the unofficial word.
我現在不能偏袒任一方  是不是？
I can't appear to be  playing favorites now, can l?
這不是因為那天的事吧？
This isn't because of the other day, is it?
哪天？
What other day?
你說過我們維持公事公辦
You said we'd keep  our professional relationship.
這就是公事公辦
Well, this is what professional feels like.
美國副總統，吉姆馬修！
The Vice President of the United States,  Jim Matthews!
謝謝
Thank you.
真高興回到布里斯托
It's good to be back in Bristol.
戰士加油！
Go, warriors!
你們都知道我，我就會吹噓
Now, you all know me. I'm a windbag.
我會滔滔不絕，講到你們睡著
I can go on until you all fall asleep,
睡上八小時，醒來我還沒說完
get eight hours of shut-eye,  and wake up to find me still yapping.
對於我左邊這位年輕人  我可有得說了
And there's a lot I could say  about this young man to my left.
事實上  我曾經質疑過他和他的理念
The truth is, I've had a lot of doubts  about him and his ideas,
他的過去
about his past,
他的資淺
about his youth.
但是你們會記得
But ifyou'll remember,
你們許多人在我首次參選  都質疑過我
a lot ofyou had doubts about me  the first time I ran.
還有第二次和第三次參選
And the second and the third.
但是在過去幾天內
But over the last few days,
跟彼得在州內各處巡迴
traveling around the state with Peter,
我得承認他贏得了我的信任
I have to admit he's won me over.
他聰明、有活力  最重要的是，他充滿鬥志
He's smart, he's energetic,  and most important, he's a fighter.
那台巴士上寫著  「重新開始！  「
Now, it says "A fresh start!"  on that bus over there.
一點也不錯
And that's the real truth,
因為這位年輕人會為本州帶來  迫切需要的嶄新開始
because this young man will give our state  the fresh start it so desperately needs.
各位女士先生  賓州下任州長
Ladies and gentlemen,  the next Governor of Pennsylvania,
彼得魯索
Peter Russo.
謝謝你，副總統先生
Thank you, Mr. Vice President.
布里斯托，大家好嗎？
How's it going, Bristol?
今天我要來談談經濟復甦
Today I'd like to talk to you  about economic recovery.
在場許多人也許知道
Now, as many of you may be aware,
主要因為我的競爭對手
mostly because my opponent
覺得需要花幾百萬元  買電視廣告談論我的過去
feels the need to spend millions of dollars  on TV ads about my past,
對於復甦，我略知一二
I know a thing or two about recovery.
我從個人的奮鬥中  學到了很多
I've learned a great deal  through my personal struggles.
我學到了如何駕馭  我的優點和決心
I've learned how to harness my strength  and my resolve,
轉為助力
make them work for me,
就像布里斯托的水車一樣
much the way your Bristol watermills
駕馭了美麗的歐特溪水力
harnessed the power of  your beautiful Otter Creek
幾年前也駕馭了  澎湃的德拉瓦河
and the mighty Delaware River years ago.
讓我告訴大家  如何讓德拉瓦河
Let me tell you how the Delaware River
振興你們未來的經濟！
will reinvigorate your economy  for years to come!
我們會把貨品運出蘇丹
We're going to get  the shipment out of Sudan.
- 太好了  - 可能需要幾周時間
-That's great.  -lt might take a few weeks,
但是我想你應該開始安排
but I think you should start  making arrangements for Botswana,
在波札納設立基地和運輸站
where you're gonna set up base camp  and the depot.
一有預算就給我
Just send me a budget  as soon as you've got one.
克萊兒，能不能找人頂替我？
Claire, is there any way  we can send someone in my place?
我以為你要去駐地
I thought you wanted to be on the ground.
我是想，不過這次不行
I would, but I can't this time.
為什麼？
Why not?
我不知道該怎麼告訴你  但已經過了三個月
I wasn't sure how to tell you this,  but I passed the 12-week mark.
你懷孕了？
You're expecting?
吉莉安，這太好了
Gillian, that's wonderful.
什麼時候發生的？  是誰的孩子？
That... When did this happen?  Who's the father?
我在海外認識  無國界醫生組織的人
There was this guy I met overseas.  Doctors Without Borders.
我們好過一陣子  後來我離開了
We had this thing. Then I left.
但是幾個月前他回到美國
But he came back to the States  a few months ago,
就是那時發生的
and that's when it happened.
反正最後不歡而散
Anyway, it didn't end well.
不過我要把孩子生下來
But I want to keep the baby.
他知道嗎？
And does he know?
他已經結婚了
He's married.
- 我不該這樣做的，我笨  - 你不用解釋
-I shouldn't have. It was stupid.  -You don't have to explain.
三月初我要請假
I'll need some time off  at the beginning of March.
沒問題
Of course.
我們當然可以找人頂替你
And absolutely,  we'll send someone else instead.
感謝你，克萊兒
I appreciate it, Claire.
不用謝
Sure.
你說三分熟？
You said medium rare?
如果需要什麼請告訴我
Just let me know if you guys need anything.
你猜剛剛誰發簡訊給我？
Who would you guess texted me just now?
我以為她能撐過兩天以上
I thought she'd last more than a couple days.
- 出去？  - 一兩個鐘頭
-Going somewhere?  -Just for an hour or two.
還剩最後一個  我要讓他就範
I got one last hold-out to whip.
魯索提案的票數是多少？
What's the vote count on Russo's bill?
你不先沖個澡  再談骯髒的事嗎？
Don't you wanna shower first  before we dirty ourselves with business?
你走了我再衝澡  票數是多少？
I'll shower after you leave.  What's the vote count?
你這種語氣  讓我不想對你坦白
Your tone doesn't inspire me  to be very forthcoming.
讓你干還不夠？  還需要特殊的語氣？
The fuck wasn't enough?  You need a special tone too?
有人今天早上用強酸漱口了
Someone washed her mouth  out with acid this morning.
無論你的內心在掙扎什麼
Whatever it is you're grappling with,
我真的沒興趣
I am sincerely not interested.
你的年紀幾乎比我大一倍
You're almost twice my age.
- 你說過你不介意  - 我是騙你的
-You said that didn't bother you.  -I lied.
如果你有女兒，她也比我大了
If you had a daughter,  she'd be older than me.
20年後，我會比你現在還年輕
In 20 years,  I'll still be younger than you are now.
依照基本算術來算，沒錯
Well, I can't argue with basic arithmetic.
你不覺得很噁心嗎？
You don't find that disgusting?
我想你要我覺得噁心
I think you want me to.
但是這也不過是兩個成年人
But I've never considered this  any more or less
你情我願的交易罷了
than a transaction  between two consenting adults.
如果你只是要一個女孩  來為你出價
If you just want the girl  who will do your bidding for you,
你已經得到了
you already have that.
為何要干我？
Why do you need to fuck me?
你要記得  主動要幽會的是你
I would remind you  that it was you who initiated our affair,
去年冬天，來敲我門的是你
and it was you  who came knocking at my door last winter.
要求結束的是我
And it was me who asked  that we stop what we're doing now.
我尊重你的要求  不過你又打電話
Which I respected  until you picked up a phone
要我今天晚上過來
and asked me to come over tonight.
因為你不給我想要的內幕  除非我先給你
Because you wouldn't give me  what I wanted unless I did.
告訴我，你為什麼要這樣做？
So tell me, why do you need this?
你似乎沒有從中得到樂趣
You don't seem to get any pleasure out of it.
我知道我根本沒有
I know I certainly don't.
我好像總是能令你滿足
I seem to always leave you satisfied.
你怎麼知道我不是裝的？
How do you know I'm not faking it?
你是裝的嗎？
Are you?
你分辨不出來  這不就很清楚嗎？
Doesn't it say a lot that you can't tell?
我趴在牆上時  你心裏在想什麼？
What do you think about  when I'm up against the wall?
一個偉人曾經說過  「人生的一切都是性…
A great man once said  that "Everything in life is about sex...
「除了性以外
"Except sex.
「性就是權力」
"Sex is about power."
你要一個婊子
So you need a whore,
那你就是個皮條客
which makes you a pimp.
我不是皮條客  只是個很慷慨的嫖客
I'm not a pimp. Just a very generous john.
好
Fine.
只要我們各自心裏都清楚  我可以扮演婊子
As long as we're clear about what this is,  I can play the whore.
現在付錢
Now pay me.
提案會通過，我們多兩票
The bill will pass. We have it by two votes.
你可以把消息轉給你的朋友  史柯斯基小姐
You can pass that along  to your friend, Ms. Skorsky.
如果她要說這種話  晚上才睡得安穩，就讓她說吧
If she must say such things  in order to sleep at night, so be it.
她對我忠貞，我無須付出代價  只是偶爾爆個料
Her loyalty costs me nothing  but the occasional crumb of news.
她恨我，我根本不在乎
Her hatefulness takes no toll at all.
給阻街女一點好處  可不只是為了要抱抱她
You don't compensate a working girl  so you can cuddle after.
最後票數…
Final voting...
許多小鎮，有些人群很好
A lot of small towns,  some really great crowds.
- 不會有巴士煞車失靈  - 最後投票機會
-No buses losing their brakes.  -Final call for voting.
拜託別這樣，你什麼時候回去？
Please, no. When do you head back?
明天，點票完畢後  我們就會開記者會
Tomorrow. We wanna do a press conference  when all the votes are in.
各位議員，現在請投票
Members, please cast your votes now.
- 你沒事吧？  - 我只是有點想嘔吐
-Are you all right?  -I'm just a little nauseous.
過一陣就好了，沒事
It'll pass. I'm okay.
- 你說待產期是3月？  - 3月14號
-You said you're due in March?  -March 14th.
你一定很興奮
It must be so exciting.
晨吐嚴重嗎？
How's the morning sickness?
最糟的已經過去了  我一天到晚想小便
I think I'm over the hump.  I have to pee all the time.
想吃奇怪的東西
Weird cravings.
再次參加巡迴的感覺真好
It was good to be on the road again.
充滿活力
Invigorating.
我們的內部資料顯示  支持率有所提升
Our internals are showing  a nice bump in the numbers.
你幫了很大的忙
You made a big difference, sir.
總統很感謝你，我也是
The President is grateful, and so am l.
團隊合作，是吧？
Well, it's a team effort, right?
失陪一下  我還沒跟你老婆打招呼
Excuse me. I have yet to say hello  to your better half.
- 史丹佛的事如何？  - 應該不錯
-How'd it go at Stanford?  -Well, I think.
系主任是共和黨人  所以沒有什麼好聊的
The Dean's a Republican,  so there was not a lot of small talk.
但是他似乎願意考慮
But he seemed open to considering it.
- 下周會有更多消息  - 那太好了
-We'll know more next week.  -That's terrific.
感謝你幫我的忙
I appreciate your helping me out.
我沒幫什麼忙  任何人都能買機票
I didn't do anything.  Anybody could book a plane ticket.
不是這樣說  你找人代替了我
That's not true. You covered for me.
我們不能忘記重要的事  對不對？
Well, we have to keep  the important things in perspective, right?
別以為我欠你人情
Don't think it's bought you any favors.
善意如果要求回報  那就不叫善意了
Kindness isn't kindness  if you expect a reward.
風雲人物！
The man of the hour!
先別這樣說，還在開票中
Not yet. The votes are still coming in.
你怎麼投票？我投贊成票
Hey, how'd you vote? I voted yes.
我差點忘了去投票
Voting. I knew I forgot something.
我們會通過的
We got this.
喝點葡萄果汁來慶祝吧
There's some sparkling grape juice  there to celebrate.
剩下30秒
Thirty seconds remaining.
30秒，情況不錯
Thirty seconds. Looking good.
大家走吧
Come on, everyone. Let's go.
大家依照黨的指示投票
Everyone's voting along party lines.
看吧，大家通力合作  就有這樣的成果
See? This is what happens  when we all stick together.
這次我們可贏得容易
This is an easy win for us.
15秒
Fifteen seconds.
現在投票
Vote now.
十秒
Ten seconds.
不可能
Fuck. This can't be happening.
各位議員，現在請投票
Members, please cast your votes now.
美國眾議院  分水嶺提案最後票數
投票結束  HR4913號提案未通過
Voting is closed. H.R. 4913 is defeated.
- 道格  - 我以為勝券在握
-Doug.  -I thought we had it.
所以這表示沒通過？
So this means it's dead?
真可惜，下了這麼大的工夫
It's such a shame. All of that hard work.
我要知道是誰說謊
I wanna know who lied.